Matt Boggie

Brooklyn, New York 917 446-8053 • mboggie@gmail.com

About

I'm an executive, futurist and team leader with deep experience in all facets of media technology, product development, cross-departmental workflow, and organizational change. Throughout my career, I've been most excited when investigating the newly possible, developing new ideas and concepts, and seeing them through to creation. My insights have transformed how companies produce products, serve customers and tell stories. I am equally comfortable debugging code alongside developers as I am addressing international symposia, and the work I've led has won recognition worldwide, making me a sought-after speaker, consultant, and contributor.

Professional Experience

Axios

JUNE 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2018

Chief Technology Officer: 2016–2018

Employee #2. Built the technology team and infrastructure powering a growing news media organization. Developed simple and trustworthy content creation tools that can expand to multiple tenants and diverse communications needs. Selected and managed software and service partners helping to deliver millions of page views, emails, and experiences each day. Guided strategic thinking for our technology platform on a 2-3 year horizon, and turned those strategies into timelines, budgets, and work assignments for a team of fifteen technologists. Worked closely with Design and Strategy to create product roadmaps that prioritize features, revenue, user engagement, and long-term strategy. Selected and deployed productivity tools to a growing staff that enabled their day-to-day work, from basic computing to security and conferencing.

THE NEW YORK TIMES R&D LAB

JUNE 2010 - JUNE 2016

Executive Director: 2013-2016

Supervised Creative Technologists and Data Scientists developing prototypes for new interactions between users and information. Reviewed technical literature, academic papers, startup investment plans, and both public and internal research on technology and innovative interactions. Developed prototypes and trial applications that illustrated aspects of predicted futures. Presented The New York Times' vision of the future of news and information to advertisers, agencies, employees, and select partners in a variety of public and private settings.

- Managed a staff of eight and a budget of \$3M while investing in new platforms for innovation
- Spoke at industry marketing and technology events, including at meetings of NewspaperNext and the International News Media Association, Journalism/Interactive, FutureEverything, WAN/IFRA, and Digital Medier in Oslo, Norway
- Wrote positions on industry issues such as Net Neutrality Legislation, Responsive Design, Ad Blocking, Platform Distribution, and Data Management Strategies.
- Was granted a U.S. Patent for a social advertising product

MATTHEW BOGGIE PAGE 2

Director of Technology Strategy: 2011–2013 Media and Technology Strategist: 2010-2011

Silver Medal, Corporate Entrepreneur Awards for Innovation Program: 2015

ACCENTURE LTD.

JUNE 1999 – JUNE 2010

Senior Manager, 2006-2010

Supervised teams of up to 10 employees in planning and delivering projects for media, entertainment, and communication clients. Defined new business processes and requirements for cross-departmental initiatives in film and broadcast divisions. Served as subject matter advisor for U. S.-based broadcast, content creation, and distribution business practices. Controlled P&L for projects up to \$5 million in revenues and two years in length. Mentored the formal career development of employees that resulted in promotions and new opportunities for the employees. Assisted in numerous financial, staffing, and quality management operations that contributed to \$100 million in annual revenue. Taught classes to company personnel on program management, technical architecture, digital asset management, and content management. Created internal training, external marketing leadership, and point-of-view materials for the company's Digital Transformation Initiatives.

- Wrote a Global Broadcast Consumer Survey analyzing consumer behavior and preferences, and presented its findings and conclusions to press in interviews and seminars.
- Conducted a detailed design and business case evaluation for digitizing a major motion picture studio's production and distribution operations. Estimates showed a potential savings of over \$130 million over 5 years.
- Analyzed methods of cost reduction for global distribution of programming for a prominent U. S. cable network, leading to recommendation and implementation of new production workflow.
- Performed an application and infrastructure assessment to a world leader in news distribution that allowed more comprehensive coverage.
- Designed and developed a content platform that backed a top-five U. S.-based news website, providing more up-to-date, relevant, and personalized content to a growing online audience.
- Designed, built, tested, and launched a programming management solution for a U. S. network that provided new capabilities for content scheduling and acquisition of programming from producers. The solution compressed schedule timelines by 10 days per month and reduced re-entry of operations data by 85%.

Manager, 2003-2006 Consultant, 2000-2003 Analyst, 1999-2000

Education

BOSTON UNIVERSITY

B.A. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, 1999

Minor: Communication Studies Honors: Magna cum Laude